popmog.com 2014-10-18

# POPMOG - Your portal for free-to-play online games

## POPMOG Data Privacy Statement

* * *

You can download the privacy in PDF format [here](https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/gamegenetics-production/files/file_uploads/59/97/POPMOG+Data+Privacy+Statement+-+Jan+7+2014.pdf) and store them on your computer.  

* * *

The protection of your personal data in relation to the POPMOG platform is important to GameGenetics GmbH, Ritterstraße 3, 10969 Berlin (hereinafter referred to as “GameGenetics”). This data privacy statement tells you what personal data we collect and how we process and use said data. 

### 1\. Object of this data privacy statement

This data privacy statement applies to certain games and community functions offered on the POPMOG platform and in particular the internet pages accessible at [www.popmog.com](http://www.popmog.com/). Both pure browser games and client-based games are included. 

Unless otherwise specified, this data privacy statement only governs the handling of your personal data by GameGenetics. In case you utilise the services of third parties (e.g. payment providers, game publishers), the data privacy terms and conditions of such third parties apply exclusively to such third-party services. GameGenetics does not verify the data privacy terms and conditions of third parties.

### 2\. Data Controller

The data controller within the meaning of the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) is GameGenetics GmbH, Ritterstraße 3, 10969 Berlin. 

In case of questions related to the protection of data privacy, please contact [info@gamegenetics.com](mailto:info@gamegenetics.com). You can contact this address at any time to ask questions about the protection of data privacy and to access or request the modification or deletion of your data that is stored by GameGenetics. Alternatively, you may also contact us by regular mail using the mailing address above. In this case, please specify your player name if possible in order to facilitate the efficient processing of your request.

### 3\. Data collection

In general, you can access the POPMOG platform without supplying us with personal data. You are always free to decide whether to provide us with your data or not. We only collect, process and use personal data with your consent unless we are already permitted to do so by statutory rules. To the extent your consent is provided electronically during registration on the POPMOG platform, we comply with statutory duties to provide information and record your consent. 

Providing personal data is required to register on the POPMOG platform, participate in raffles or subscribe to our newsletter. Examples of these data include your name, address, e-mail address and other personal data requested by GameGenetics on a case-by-case basis. In many cases, the services of GameGenetics can be used under a pseudonym. Users are encouraged to make use of this option. 

In addition, certain data such as the IP address, browser type and access times are automatically transmitted to us by your computer and stored on our server. Except for the purpose of pursuing the unauthorised use of our internet presence, we only evaluate these data for statistical purposes and to render services. In doing so, the data are rendered anonymous as far as possible. 

In order to make the use of the POPMOG platform as simple and comfortable as possible for you, we use so-called cookies, just as many other companies do. As a rule, these cookies are automatically deleted from your hard drive after the end of your visit to our website. Your internet browser can be set to generally reject cookies. However, this may restrict or make the use of the POPMOG platform impossible due to technical reasons.

### 4\. Use of data

We use your personal data to tailor our services according to demand and continuously improve them. 

GameGenetics uses your personal information to establish, carry on and administer your contractual relationship with GameGenetics and to process payments. In particular, the proper administration of the contractual relationship includes monitoring compliance with the terms of use and game rules. 

When you use community functions such as forums, chats, personal message services or player profiles on the POPMOG platform, we collect, process and use the information entered by you in this process to the extent required for the use of the community functions. This means that your communication content is saved by GameGenetics and, within the framework of the POPMOG platform and depending on the type of service you are using, is either made accessible to all other players (e.g. open forums) or only certain other player (e.g. restricted forums, personal messages). 

We also use your data in order to communicate with you. This includes e-mail notification about news related to our services, if applicable. Thus we use your data in order to regularly inform you of products, services and certain events related to our services that may be of interest to you. As part of the respective information, we will inform you about the option to discontinue notification. 

Finally, we also use your data to prevent abuse of our website and pursue unauthorised access.

### 5\. Transmission of data

Of course your personal data are not sold to third parties. GameGenetics only releases the personal data received from you to third parties as follows: 

We cooperate with payment providers (for example credit card companies, banks, PayPal, mobile wireless services, collection agencies etc.), providers that prepare and process statistics and IT service providers (e.g. computer centres, host providers, backup services, database services). These service providers only have access to your personal data to the extent required in order to meet their obligations. The service providers are obligated to treat your personal data in accordance with this data privacy statement and the applicable data protection laws. 

In particular, GameGenetics will provide your data to the developers of certain games which are accessible via thhe POPMOG login. You decide which developers those are by choosing the games you play. The precise contact information, especially the address and website of the respective developer, are always available on the overview page of the respective game. 

In case GameGenetics, companies controlled by GameGenetics, individual subsidiaries or parts of the company are sold, your customer information is generally transferred along with the part of the company being transferred. However, your data is of course also protected by this data privacy statement and the applicable data protection laws in this case.

As part of our work with Google we collect anonymous user data and provide them with the help of our Bidder (Google DoubleClick Bid Manager) to pass on to Google. To get more information visit [Google Privacy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).

### 6\. Deletion of data, data security

Insofar as your data are no longer required for the above-mentioned purposes, including billing or for tax or other legal reasons, they will be deleted.

### 7\. Data security

We process the information collected from you in accordance with German data protection law. All employees are obligated to maintain data secrecy and comply with the data protection regulations, and have been instructed accordingly.

## Consent to the collection, processing and use of my personal data

  1. I agree that GameGenetics GmbH, Ritterstraße 3, 10969 Berlin (hereinafter referred to as “GameGenetics”) is permitted to collect, process and use my personal data (e.g. name, address and e-mail address) in order to establish, carry on and administer my contractual relationship in regards to the POPMOG platform within the framework of the POPMOG data privacy statement. 

  2. I agree that GameGenetics may provide my personal data to related companies as well as the partner companies and authorised service providers identified in the POPMOG data privacy statement or attachments to the same and the respective game developers identified on the overview pages of the games played by me, provided they are either subject to this data privacy statement or assure at least equivalent protection of my personal data. Service providers authorised by GameGenetics are only permitted to process and use my personal data to fulfil their respective obligations. 

  3. I agree that GameGenetics is permitted to collect, process and use my personal data for marketing measures, e.g. to send out e-mail newsletters. 

  4. I also agree that, in case GameGenetics, companies related to GameGenetics, individual subsidiaries or parts of the company are sold, my personal data can be transferred to the buyer along with the part of the company being transferred. 

I am aware that I can revoke this declaration of consent with effect for the future at any time in whole or in part via e-mail to [info[at]gamegenetics.com](mailto:info@gamegenetics.com) or by regular mail to GameGenetics at the address above.
